A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Safety and Health Codes Board, 1967-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Safety and Health Codes Board, 1967-2005
The Library of Virginia
50318, 50384
16 cu. ft. (16 boxes)
Virginia Safety and Health Codes Board
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Dept. of Labor and Industry on 13 February 2012 [Accession 50318].
Transferred from the Dept. of Labor and Industry on 14 March 2012 [Accession 50384].
Biographical Information
In 1962, the Virginia General Assembly established the Safety Codes Commission with power to make rules and regulations governing safety operations. The Commission was revised by the General Assembly in 1972 and continues as the Safety and Health Codes Board. The 14-member Board is authorized to adopt, alter, amend and repeal rules and regulations for the Department of Labor and Industry to protect the occupational safety and health of employees in Virginia. This responsibility includes the state plan agreement with federal OSHA to effect compliance with the Federal Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, Boiler and Pressure Vessel Safety, and the Commonwealth's Asbestos and Lead Contractor Notification and Inspection Programs. Twelve members of the Board are appointed by the Governor for a 4-year term and, in accordance with statute, are drawn from various industries to be a mix of employee/employer representatives and the general public. The remaining two members of the Board are the Executive Director of the Department of Environmental Quality and the Commissioner of Health. Both positions serve ex-officio.
Scope and Content
Minutes and related attachments, 1967-2005, documenting the meetings and activities of the Virginia Safety and Health Codes Board. Also includes agendas, briefing packages, correspondence, transcripts and regulatory reviews.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series.
Series I: Minutes, 1986-1991 [Accession 50318]
Series II: Minutes, 1967-2005 [Accession 50384]
Contents List
- Series I: Minutes, 1986-1991., Extent: 7 cu. ft. (7 boxes). (Box 1-7)
  - Minutes, 1986 January - 1987 March (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1987 March - 1988 July (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1988 November; 1989 March; 1989 November (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1989 January - October (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1989 November - 1990 November (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 1990 September - 1991 April (Box 6)
  - Minutes, 1991 January - December (Box 7)
- Series II: Minutes, 1967-2005., Extent: 9 cu. ft. (9 boxes). (Box 1-9)
  - Minutes, 1967 August - 1991 July (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1972 - 1984 (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 1985 - 1986 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, 1987 March - 1989 March (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1989 June - 1990 April (Box 5)
  - Minutes, 1990 July - 1992 June (Box 6)
  - Minutes, 1992 May - 1993 November (Box 7)
  - Minutes, 1993 December - 1997 September (Box 8)
  - Minutes, 1998 February - 2005 (Box 9)